Raymond A. Rich Papers
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
- 3. Photographic Materials, 1936 - 1990s; 3; Box: 18 - 24
  - Subseries 3.2: Business, 1936 - 1982; 3.2; Boxes: 18 - 21 Folders: 5 - 14, 1 - 15, 1 - 14, 1 - 11
    - Business Dinners at Raymond A. Rich&#39;s Homes, 1979 (Folder 11, Box 18)
    - Business Dinners at Raymond A. Rich&#39;s Homes, 1978-1980, Undated (Folder 12, Box 18)
    - Business Dinners at Raymond A. Rich&#39;s Homes, 1979-1980, Undated (Folder 13, Box 18)
    - Business Dinners at Raymond A. Rich&#39;s Homes, 1978-1981, Undated (Folder 14, Box 18)
    - Business Dinners at Raymond A. Rich&#39;s Homes, 1980, Undated (Folder 1, Box 19)
    - Business Dinners at Raymond A. Rich&#39;s Homes, 1980-1981 (Folder 2, Box 19)
    - Business Dinners at Raymond A. Rich&#39;s Homes, 1981, Undated (Folder 3, Box 19)
    - Business Events, 1976, 1979, 1987, Undated (Folder 4, Box 19)
    - Canadian Gasoline Event (See Oversized Box 7 File 1), Undated (Folder 5, Box 19)
    - Dinner Events at the Waldorf-Astoria, 1977, 1979, 1980, Undated (Folder 6, Box 19)
    - Dinner Events at the Waldorf-Astoria, 1981, Undated (Folder 7, Box 19)
    - Early Business Career Photos (See Oversized Box 6 File 1), Undated (Folder 8, Box 19)
    - Fitrol Corporation, December 5, 1979 (Folder 9, Box 19)
    - Fitrol Corporation Board Event, 1976, Undated (Folder 10, Box 19)
    - General Electric, Circa 1935-1941 (Folder 11, Box 19)
    - Miscellaneous, Circa 1950-1970s (Folder 12, Box 19)
    - Philco Convention, 1950 (Folder 13, Box 19)
    - Philco Convention, 1951 (Folder 14, Box 19)
    - Philco Conventions, 1949-1953 (Folder 15, Box 19)
    - Philco Corporation, Circa 1948-1956 (Folder 1, Box 20)
    - Rail X Ranch Meeting, 1968 (Folder 2, Box 20)
    - Rail X Ranch Meeting, 1969 (Folder 3, Box 20)
    - Rail X Ranch Meeting, 1967, 1977 (Folder 4, Box 20)
    - Rail X Ranch Meeting, Undated (Folder 5, Box 20)
    - Raymond A. Rich Business Events, 1979-1980, Undated (Folder 6, Box 20)
    - Raymond A. Rich Business Events (See Oversized Box 7 File 2), Undated (Folder 7, Box 20)
    - Raymond A. Rich Early Business Career, 1936, 1950, 1952, Undated (Folder 8, Box 20)
    - Raymond A. Rich Early Business Career, 1936, 1949, Undated (Folder 9, Box 20)
    - Raymond A. Rich Early Business Career, 1964,Undated (Folder 10, Box 20)
    - Raymond A. Rich in the Boardroom (See Oversized Box 7 File 3), 1965, Undated (Folder 11, Box 20)
    - Raymond A. Rich in the Boardroom, Undated (Folder 12, Box 20)
    - Raymond A. Rich in the Boardroom, 1976, Undated (Folder 13, Box 20)
    - Sale of GWB Event, 1980, Undated (Folder 14, Box 20)
    - Scrapbook of Business Events at Raymond A. Rich&#39;s Homes (See Oversized Box 5), Undated (Folder 1, Box 21)
    - Scrapbook of the US Filter Corporation Controller Conference at Raymond A. Rich&#39;s Home (See Oversized Box 4), 1979 (Folder 2, Box 21)
    - Slides of Business Dinners at Raymond A. Rich&#39;s Homes, 1980-1981, 1983 (Folder 3, Box 21)
    - US Filter Board of Directors (See Oversized Box 7 File 4), 1976 (Folder 4, Box 21)
    - US Filter Controller Conference, 1979 (Folder 5, Box 21)
    - United States Filter Corporation Events, 1980, Undated (Folder 6, Box 21)
    - United States Filter Corporation - Riley/USF Dinner, January 24, 1980 (Folder 7, Box 21)
    - United State Filter Corporation - the Flick Group Reception, May 26, 1980 (Folder 8, Box 21)
    - US Filter Event at Burg Wartenstein (See Oversized Box 7 File 5), 1982 (Folder 9, Box 21)
    - United States Filter - Tiger Award Dinner, Circa 1970s (Folder 10, Box 21)
    - Van Daren, Nowland, and Schaldermundt, June 19, 1946 (Folder 11, Box 21)
  - Subseries 3.3: Committee for Economic Development, 1942 - 1944; 3.3; Box: 12 Folder: 21
    - Committee for Economic Development, Circa 1942 - 1944 (Folder 12, Box 21)
  - Subseries 3.4: O.H. Payne, 3.4; Boxes: 21 - 22 Folders: 13 - 15, 1 - 4
    - Early Payne Mansion Photos, 1915-1916, Undated (Folder 13, Box 21)
    - Early Payne Mansion Photos - Marist Brothers Chapel, Undated (Folder 14, Box 21)
    - Early Payne Mansion Photo Negatives, Undated (Folder 15, Box 21)
    - O.H. Payne, Circa 1860s - 1910s (Folder 1, Box 22)
    - O.H. Payne - Aphrodite, Circa 1910s (Folder 2, Box 22)
    - O.H. Payne Mansion, Circa 1910s (Folder 3, Box 22)
    - Payne Mansion Property Advertisement, Undated (Folder 4, Box 22)
  - Subseries 3.5: Omega Mansion, 1983 - 2001; 3.5; Box: 22 Folders: 5 - 18
    - Omega Mansion, 1986, 1989, Undated (Folder 5, Box 22)
    - Omega Mansion - Construction, Undated (Folder 6, Box 22)
    - Omega Mansion Construction (See Oversized Box 6 File 2), Undated (Folder 7, Box 22)
    - Omega Mansion Decor, Undated (Folder 8, Box 22)
    - Omega Mansion - Exterior, 1983, 1987, 1989, 2009, Undated (Folder 9, Box 22)
    - Omega Mansion - Exterior (See Oversized Box 7 File 6), Undated (Folder 10, Box 22)
    - Omega Mansion - Exterior (See Oversized Box 6 File 3), Undated (Folder 11, Box 22)
    - Omega Mansion - Exterior Shots, Circa 1990s (Folder 12, Box 22)
    - Omega Mansion - Interior, 1989, Undated (Folder 13, Box 22)
    - Omega Mansion - Interior, 1996, Undated (Folder 14, Box 22)
    - Omega Mansion - Interior and Detail Shots, Circa 1990s (Folder 15, Box 22)
    - Omega Mansion - Interior and exterior Shots, some with Raymond A. Rich and Claire Carlson, 1989 (Folder 16, Box 22)
    - Omega Mansion - Pre-Construction (Folder 17, Box 22)
    - Omega Mansion Scrapbook (See Oversized Box 4), 2001 (Folder 18, Box 22)
  - Subseries 3.6: Personal, 1943 - 2003; 3.6; Boxes: 22 - 24 Folders: 19 - 23, 1 - 18, 1 - 8
    - Early Photos from Friends, 1943-1944, Undated (Folder 19, Box 22)
    - Early Raymond A. Rich and Family Photos, 1916-1930s (Folder 20, Box 22)
    - Early Raymond A. Rich and Family, 1949, 1956, Undated (Folder 21, Box 22)
    - Raymond A. Rich and Family, 1977, 1979, 1981 (Folder 22, Box 22)
    - Raymond A. Rich and Family, 1988 (Folder 23, Box 22)
    - Raymond A. Rich and Family at Omega Mansion, 1996, Undated (Folder 1, Box 23)
    - Raymond A. Rich and his Boat (See Oversized Box 7 File 7), Undated (Folder 2, Box 23)
    - Raymond A. Rich at his Homes (See Oversized Box 6 File 4), 1981, 1983, 2003, 2009, Undated (Folder 3, Box 23)
    - Raymond A. Rich at his Homes, 1978, 1982-1985, 1987, Undated (Folder 4, Box 23)
    - Raymond A. Rich at his Homes, 1980, Undated (Folder 5, Box 23)
    - Raymond A. Rich at his Homes, 2001- 2002, Undated (Folder 6, Box 23)
    - Raymond A. Rich at his Homes (See Oversized Box 7 File 8), Undated (Folder 7, Box 23)
    - Raymond A. Rich Early Years - with his Friends, Undated (Folder 8, Box 23)
    - Raymond A. Rich Headshots, Undated (Folder 9, Box 23)
    - Raymond A. Rich Headshots (See Oversized Box 7 File 9), Undated (Folder 10, Box 23)
    - Raymond A. Rich Headshot (See Oversized Box 3), Undated (Folder 11, Box 23)
    - Raymond A. Rich Headshots, Undated (Folder 12, Box 23)
    - Raymond A. Rich Headshots, Circa 1930s - 1980s (Folder 13, Box 23)
    - Raymond A. Rich Headshot Negatives, 1977 (Folder 14, Box 23)
    - Raymond A. Rich&#39;s Homes, 1979-1980, 1987, 1993, Undated (Folder 15, Box 23)
    - Raymond A. Rich&#39;s Homes, 1973, 1982, 2009, Undated (Folder 16, Box 23)
    - Raymond A. Rich&#39;s Homes (See Oversized Box 6 File 5), 1981-1982, Undated (Folder 17, Box 23)
    - Raymond A. Rich&#39;s Homes (See Oversized Box 6 File 6), 1982, 2003, Undated (Folder 18, Box 23)
    - Raymond A. Rich&#39;s Homes, 1982, Undated (Folder 1, Box 24)
    - Raymond A. Rich&#39;s Homes, Undated (Folder 2, Box 24)
    - Raymond A. Rich&#39;s Homes, Undated (Folder 3, Box 24)
    - Raymond A. Rich&#39;s Homes, Undated (Folder 4, Box 24)
    - Raymond A. Rich&#39;s Homes (See Oversized Box 7 File 10), Undated (Folder 5, Box 24)
    - Raymond A. Rich&#39;s Homes (See oversized Box 6 File 7), 1982, Undated (Folder 6, Box 24)
    - Raymond A. Rich&#39;s Homes (See Oversized Box 6 File 8), 1982,1985, Undated (Folder 7, Box 24)
    - Travel Photos of Raymond A. Rich (See Oversized Box 6 File 9), Undated (Folder 8, Box 24)
  - Subseries 3.7: Miscellaneous, 1896 - 1979; 3.7; Box: 24 Folders: 9 - 11
    - Miscellaneous, 1896, Undated (Folder 9, Box 24)
    - Miscellaneous, Circa 1950s- 1970s (Folder 10, Box 24)
    - Miscellaneous (See Oversized Box 7 File 11), Undated (Folder 11, Box 24)
  - Subseries 3.8: World War II, 1944 - 1994; 3.8; Box: 24 Folders: 12 - 18
    - Fort Schuyler, Circa 1994 (Folder 12, Box 24)
    - &#34;Japan Ray&#34, Circa 1945 (Folder 13, Box 24)
    - Official US Army Photos - Set No. 163 - Okinawa Offensive, Circa 1940s (Folder 14, Box 24)
    - Official US Marine Corps Photos - Set No. 16 - Okinawa Operations, Circa 1940s (Folder 15, Box 24)
    - Postcards, Circa 1940s (Folder 16, Box 24)
    - Raymond A. Rich Military Photos, 1944, Undated (Folder 17, Box 24)
    - Raymond A. Rich and Shipmates, Circa 1944 - 1946 (Folder 18, Box 24)
- 4. Audiovisual Materials, 1950 - 2005; 4; Boxes: 25 - 27
  Series contains videos from businesses, personal, and commerical
  - Subseries 4.1: Business, 1981 - 1982; 4.1; Box: 25 Items: 1 - 19
    - United States Filter Corporation - Raymond A. Rich Appreciation Dinner (Audio) [see oversized box RAR-06], 1981 November 12; Item 1 (Box 25)
    - United States Filter Corporation - Raymond A. Rich Appreciation Dinner (Video) [see oversized box RAR-06], 1981 November 12; Item 2 (Box 25)
    - Burg Wartenstein - Raymond A. Rich [see oversized box RAR-06], 1993 June 23; Item 3 (Box 25)
    - U.S. Filter Corp. - &#34;R.A.R. Appreciation Dinner&#34; - November 12, 1981 - Reel #1 - Edited Master (3/4&#34; tape - Video), 1981 December 17; Item 4 (Box 25)
    - U.S. Filter Corp. - &#34;R.A.R. Appreciation Dinner&#34; - November 12, 1981 - Reel #2 - Edited Master (3/4&#34; tape - Video), 1981 December 17; Item 5 (Box 25)
    - U.S. Filter Corp. - &#34;R.A.R. Appreciation Dinner&#34;- November 12, 1981 - Reel #3 - Edited Master (3/4&#34; tape - Video), 1981 December 17; Item 6 (Box 25)
    - U.S. Filter Corp.-&#34;R.A.R. Appreciation Dinner&#34;-November 12, 1981-Edward T. Veith Complete Speech (3/4&#34; tape - video), 1981 November 12; Item 7 (Box 25)
    - The Chartmakers, U.S. Filter Corp. - R.A.R. Appreciation Dinner - Reel #1 / Part 1 (3/4&#34; tape - Video), 1981 November 12; Item 8 (Box 25)
    - The Chartmakers, U.S. Filter Corp. - R.A.R. Appreciation Dinner - Reel #3 / Part 1 (3/4&#34; tape - Video), 1981 November 12; Item 9 (Box 25)
    - U.S. Filter Corp. --&#34; R.A.R. Appreciation Dinner&#34;(VHS), 1981 November 12; Item 10 (Box 25)
    - U.S. Filter Corp. --&#34;R.A.R. Appreciation Dinner&#34;-Reel #1 (Betamax), 1982 April 28; Item 11 (Box 25)
    - U.S. Filter Corp.-&#34;R.A.R. Appreciation Dinner&#34;-Reel #2 (Betamax), 1982 April 28; Item 12 (Box 25)
    - U.S. Filter Corp.-&#34;R.A.R. Appreciation Dinner&#34;-Reel #3 (Betamax), 1982 April 28; Item 13 (Box 25)
    - U.S. Filter Corp.-&#34;R.A.R. Appreciation Dinner&#34;-November 12, 1981-Edward T. Veith Complete Speech (Betamax), 1981 November 12; Item 14 (Box 25)
    - Burg Wartenstein-R.A.R. (VHS), undated; Item 15 (Box 25)
    - Wartenstein (VHS), 1993; Item 16 (Box 25)
    - Waldorf Dinner (VHS), 1981; Item 17 (Box 25)
    - Waldorf Dinner (VHS), undated; Item 18 (Box 25)
    - Waldorf Dinner (VHS), undated; Item 19 (Box 25)
  - Subseries 4.2: Personal, 4.2; Box: 26 Items: 1 - 28
    - Christmas Carols at Omega - Home Video (VHS), 1998; Item 1 (Box 26)
    - 2147A, 1700A - Home Video (VHS), undated; Item 2 (Box 26)
    - Rich/Marist Bulkhead (c4) Underwater Inspection (VHS), 2003 July 23; Item 3 (Box 26)
    - Ray Rich Boathouse Inspection (VHS), 2003 August 9; Item 4 (Box 26)
    - Ray Rich Boathouse - Repairs - U/W Inspection (VHS), 2003 September 21; Item 5 (Box 26)
    - Ray Rich Boathouse - Repairs - U/W Inspection - Hudson Marine, Inc. (914) 643 7159 - Home Video (VHS), 2003 September 21; Item 6 (Box 26)
    - Marco - Home Video (VHS), undated; Item 7 (Box 26)
    - II Creeks Ranch 1,400,000 - Home Video (VHS) - Includes card: &#34;The Carlson Review: Note: On the video there&#39;s a pause on it, and then it continues till the end.&#34, undated; Item 8 (Box 26)
    - 332 Acres - Home Video (VHS), undated; Item 9 (Box 26)
    - Old Master Replicas by David Pakter - Home Video (VHS), undated; Item 10 (Box 26)
    - E.T.: The Extra-Terrestrial - Home Video (VHS), circa 1990s; Item 11 (Box 26)
    - James Bond Thunderball - Home Video (VHS), undated; Item 12 (Box 26)
    - 1) Revenge of the Pink Panther - Peter Sellers, Herbert Lom, Dyan Cannon 2) Executive Suite - Robert Wise, William Holden, June Allyson, Barbara Stanwyck, Fredric March, Shelley Winters, Walter Pidgeon Home Video (VHS), 1978 1954; Item 13 (Box 26)
    - Unlabeled Video Cassette (VHS), undated; Item 14 (Box 26)
    - Unlabeled Video Cassette (VHS), undated; Item 15 (Box 26)
    - Unlabeled Video Cassette (VHS), undated; Item 16 (Box 26)
    - Unlabeled Video Cassette (VHS), undated; Item 17 (Box 26)
    - Blank Sealed Video Cassette (VHS), undated; Item 18 (Box 26)
    - Blank Sealed Video Cassette (VHS), undated; Item 19 (Box 26)
    - Back to Bataan - J. Wayne - Home Video (Beta), undated; Item 20 (Box 26)
    - 1) Kentucky Derby - 5; 2) Captain Blood; 3) Eagle Has Landed - Home Video (Beta), undated; Item 21 (Box 26)
    - The Longest Day: W.W. II - Home Video (Beta), undated; Item 22 (Box 26)
    - Yellowbeard - Home Video (Beta), undated; Item 23 (Box 26)
    - The Maltese Falcon - Home Video (Beta), undated; Item 24 (Box 26)
    - Easy Money - Home Video (Beta), undated; Item 25 (Box 26)
    - Oklahoma - Home Video (Beta), undated; Item 26 (Box 26)
    - Sony Dynamicron L-750 Video Cassette - Blank sealed (Beta), undated; Item 27 (Box 26)
    - Unmarked Video Cassette without case (Beta), undated; Item 28 (Box 26)
  - Subseries 4.3: Commercial, 1950 - 2005; 4.3; Box: 27 Items: 1 - 34
    - Great Castles of Europe - France and Spain - The Learning Channel (VHS), 1994; Item 1 (Box 27)
    - Edinburgh Military Tattoo 1987 From the Castle Esplanade (VHS), Item 2 (Box 27)
    - Seeing the West Highlands of Scotland - West Ardnamurchan - Scenic Video No. 1 - The video series reflecting the rare and special beauty of the Highland scene (VHS) [with plastic case], undated; Item 3 (Box 27)
    - Seeing the West Highlands of Scotland - West Ardnamurchan - Scenic Video No. 1 - The video series reflecting the rare and special beauty of the Highland scene (VHS) [without plastic case], undated; Item 4 (Box 27)
    - Peter de Savary Esq. - Glenborrodale Castle (VHS), 1990 August 29; Item 5 (Box 27)
    - The Frick Collection: An Introduction (VHS), 1995; Item 6 (Box 27)
    - Carreras Domingo Pavarotti in concert MEHTA - Terme di Caracalla, Roma (VHS), 1990 July 7; Item 7 (Box 27)
    - Video Film Classics - Flying Deuces (1939) - Laurel Hardy (VHS), 1984; Item 8 (Box 27)
    - Video Film Classics - Thief of Bagdad (1924 - Silent Film) - Douglas Fairbanks and Julanne Johnston (VHS), 1984; Item 9 (Box 27)
    - Columbia Pictures Presents the Sam Spiegel-David Lean Production of "Lawrence of Arabia" - Part 1 (Beta), 1962; Item 10 (Box 27)
    - Columbia Pictures Presents the Sam Spiegel-David Lean Production of "Lawrence of Arabia" - Part 2 (Beta), 1962; Item 11 (Box 27)
    - Columbia Pictures Presents a Sam Spiegel Production of "The Bridge on the River Kwai" - William Holden, Alec Guinness, and Jack Hawkins - Part 1 (Beta), 1981; Item 12 (Box 27)
    - Columbia Pictures Presents a Sam Spiegel Production of "The Bridge on the River Kwai"- William Holden, Alec Guinness, and Jack Hawkins - Part 2 (Beta), 1981; Item 13 (Box 27)
    - The Nostalgia Merchant - Sinbad the Sailor(1947) - Douglas Fairbanks, Jr., Maureen O &#39;Hara, and Anthony Quinn - A Video Classic (Beta), 1978; Item 14 (Box 27)
    - The Nostalgia Merchant - The Hunchback of Notre Dame (1939) - Charles Laughton, Maureen O&#39;Hara, and Edmond O&#39;Brien - A Video Classic (Beta), 1978; Item 15 (Box 27)
    - Patton - A Twentieth Century-Fox Film - George C. Scott and Karl Malden - Part 1 (Beta), 1969; Item 16 (Box 27)
    - Patton - A Twentieth Century-Fox Film - George C. Scott and Karl Malden - Part 2 (Beta), 1969; Item 17 (Box 27)
    - An MGM/CBS Home Video Presentation - Charlton Heston in Ben Hur (1959) - Part 1 (Beta), 1980; Item 18 (Box 27)
    - An MGM/CBS Home Video Presentation - Charlton Heston in Ben Hur (1959) - Part 2 (Beta), 1980; Item 19 (Box 27)
    - Paramount Pictures Presents Hal Wallis&#39; Production of "True Grit" - John Wayne, Glen Campbell, Kim Darby - Part 1 (Beta), 1979; Item 20 (Box 27)
    - Paramount Pictures Presents Hal Wallis&#39; Production of "True Grit" - John Wayne, Glen Campbell, Kim Darby - Part 2 (Beta), 1979; Item 21 (Box 27)
    - Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade (VHS), 1989; Item 22 (Box 27)
    - CBS Fox Video - Patton (1969) - George C. Scott and Karl Malden - Part 1 and Part 2 (VHS), 1986; Item 23 (Box 27)
    - Harvey - James Stewart - MCA Home Video (VHS), 1950; Item 24 (Box 27)
    - Red River - John Wayne - MGM/UA Home Video - Restored Director&#39;s Cut (VHS), 1948; Item 25 (Box 27)
    - Embassy Home Entertainment - Victory at Sea - Special Collector&#39;s Edition - Volume 1 (VHS), 1987; Item 26 (Box 27)
    - Embassy Home Entertainment - Victory at Sea - Special Collector&#39;s Edition - Volume 2 (VHS), 1987; Item 27 (Box 27)
    - Embassy Home Entertainment - Victory at Sea - Special Collector&#39;s Edition - Volume 3 (VHS), 1987; Item 28 (Box 27)
    - Embassy Home Entertainment - Victory at Sea - Special Collector&#39;s Edition - Volume 4 (VHS), 1987; Item 29 (Box 27)
    - Embassy Home Entertainment - Victory at Sea - Special Collector&#39;s Edition - Volume 5 (VHS), 1987; Item 30 (Box 27)
    - The Aviator: A Martin Scorsese Picture - Leonardo DiCaprio - 2-Disc Widescreen Edition (DVD), 2004; Item 31 (Box 27)
    - Master and Commander: The Far Side of the World - Russell Crowe - Video (DVD), 2004; Item 32 (Box 27)
    - The Ultimate Gift - From the best-selling novel by Jim Stovall - Drew Fuller, Bill Cobbs, Abigail Breslin, Brian Dennehy, and James Garner - Video (DVD), 2006; Item 33 (Box 27)
    - Leonard Berstein conducts West Side Story - Kiri Te Kanawa, Jose Carreras, Tatiana Troyanos, Kurt Ollmann, Marilyn Horne - Deutsche Grammophone Digital Recording - Audio - (Two tape cassettes - Chromium Dioxide ), 1985; Item 34 (Box 27)